NITIN JADHAV

FRONTEND DEVELOPER & DESIGNER

Pune, India ● +91 9623682301 ● nitinjadhav@gmail.com ● www.nitinj.com



A passionate UI Developer who cares about accessibility and performance. Builds beautiful, highly usable frontends using cutting edge tech. Takes pride in simplifying complex interfaces and mastering the craft. Strives to be minimalistic in both code and design. Possesses 11+ years of solid industry experience.

KEY SKILLS

Frontend: JavaScript / ES6 / ESNext, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3, CSS Pre-processors

ReactJS & Redux, Angular 2+, AngularJS, WebComponents

Webpack, npm, Parcel, jQuery, Bootstrap, Responsive & mobile first design, various linting & unit testing tools

Server: Node JS (familiar), Java (Familiar), MySQL database(familiar), MongoDB(familiar), GraphQL, Docker, Nginx, Git

Other: Adobe XD, Sketch and various other tools. Good understanding of accessibility standards,

Usability protocols.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Lead Developer, QiO Technologies Ltd

Feb 2016 - Now

- Led and developed Authorized Service Center frontend, a large size project for Rolls Royce, Germany
- Architected and developed *Daily Progress Report* project frontend for McDermott, USA. *Did optimization of webapp that resulted in 60% reduced load time*
- Did Several POCs for prospective clients including Rolls Royce Singapore, that resulted in winning multiple projects.
- Delivered product demos and training to many clients onsite

Consultant Developer for Hewlett-Packard India and other clients

June 2015 - Feb 2016

- Designed/Developed both UX & UI for Incident Reporting Portal for Hewlett-Packard India
- Developed UX and design system for *Property Manager*, for an Australian company
- Full stack development of Customer Management Portal for Date Panchang, a horoscope company

Senior Frontend Developer, MediaOcean

Feb 2014 - June 2015

• Worked on UI development of company's flagship advertising product *Prisma*

Senior Frontend Developer, Airtight Networks Inc (Now Arista)

Sept 2010 – Jan 2014

- Developed UI and component library for *Airtight Management Console*, a wireless security product
- Designed and developed Javascript & GWT based application framework company product line. This UI framework is now standard through company's many products

Software Developer, Persistent Systems

June 2007 - Sept 2010

- Worked on Protectoria, a secure mailing platform as developer Java, JSP, JSF and HTML/JavaScript.
- Worked on Groundwork open source network monitoring tool developed portlet framework which is still in use

Internship, Persistent Systems - Leading company in outsourced product development Internship, Date Panchang Technologies, Pune

2007

2004

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Applications, 2007

University of Pune, 3-year full time computer science curriculum

Bachelor of Computer Science, 2004

University of Pune, Specializes in data structures, databases, networking

ACHIEVEMENTS

Wave award of Appreciation (2014, MediaOcean)
Star developer award, Multiple Spot awards for Performance (Persistent Systems, 2007-2010)
Winner with 1st place, Pune Inter-college Java Programming competition (2007)

PERSONAL

Nationality: Indian

Languages: English (Proficient), Hindi, Marathi

Marital status: Married

Interests: Gaming, Trekking, Teaching